# Nader Ben Ammar

nader.ben.ammar@gmail.com, Mobile: +21698340092

linkedin.com/in/naderbenammar



#### Summary

I am currently Country Manager taking care of Tunisia for Ericsson. Overall, my experience spans sales & business development, customer relationship management, account management and budgeting / finance, staff leadership & mentoring, the development & implementation of commercial strategy, planning, driving process improvements with the goal to become a strategic partner and advisor to my customers, discovering new opportunities to work together for mutual benefit.

### **Experience**



# Country Manager

Ericsson

Dec 2021 - Present

Having overall responsibility on the country business. On a weekly/monthly basis: P&L actuals and forecast, working capital and cash flow follow-up. Managing customer relationship at C-level. Supervise adherence to group commercial strategy and translation into local dimension. Ensure follow-up actions, among different functions, to enhance efficiency, optimize processes and speedup execution. Ambassador and main responsible towards Governmental entities, regulation bodies and main spokesperson for media relations. Ensuring local adherence to company business ethics as well as health and security measures.

## Key Account Manager

Ericsson

Feb 2020 - November 2021

Overall responsibility on one of the main operators in Algeria. P&L actuals and forecast follow-up as well as cash collection. Managing sales opportunities from qualification till full deal winning and oversee the delivery phase until completion. Taking leadership role in steering group meetings. Pushing team for process adherence and effort optimization while enhancing efficiency for a customer satisfaction. Main portfolio exposure in Business Support Systems. Having relationship with CMO and recommending enhancements of portfolio with new features and services for B2C.



#### Senior Account Manager MVNO & Government

Ericsson

Sep 2017 - Feb 2020

Taking role as the second main interface towards Governmental entities to enable new business opportunities as well as driving Sustainability and Corporate Responsibility initiatives in addition to managing sales opportunities towards MVNOs and some main customers like Tunisie Telecom and Ooredoo Tunisia.



# Senior Account Manager Industry & Society

Ericsson

May 2014 - Aug 2017

Creating and maintaining a successful, satisfied and loyal customer base and optimize orders (OB), sales (NS) and unadjusted margins (UM). Industries:

- Safety & Security
- Utilities, Oil&Gas
- Intelligent Transport Systems, Automotive, Maritime
- IoT

# Senior Account Manager

**Ericsson** 

Jan 2007 - Dec 2016

Develop and Maintain Relationship, P&L Accountability. Mainly in

BSS area with incumbent operator and MVNOs

# Marketing Product Manager

Huawei

May 2005 - Dec 2006

Customer Relationship and Promotion of new VAS solutions with main operators like Tunisie Telecom and Ooredoo.

# Technical Bid Manager

Siemens

Dec 2004 - Jun 2005

Evaluation and Preparation of Technical Solutions for bid proposals.

# Business Development Manager

**GET WIRELESS** 

Sep 2003 - Dec 2004

VAS Pioneer in Tunisia. Driving new potential opportunities for end user services based on SMS.

#### **Education**

#### Politecnico di Milano

Doctor Engineer, Telecommunications Engineering 1996 - 2003

#### **Licenses & Certifications**



# SET2WIN Sales Foundation Key Account Manager badge 2021 - Ericsson

#### Skills

Team Cohesion • Problem Solving • Financial acumen • Doer • Critical Thinking • Contract Labor • Strong Leadership • Fluent English, French, Arabic and Italian • Business Development • Account Management